PIJUSH KUMAR JOARDAR () Featured

Senior Software Developer seeking roles in IT Project Management, Software Development, Software Design, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Agile Methodology, Software Testing, Software Quality
Assurance, ASP. Net, Javascript, jQuery, MVC, SQL Server



Current Designation: Senior Software Developer Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Cognizant Softvision Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Kolkata Highest Degree: MCA [ER and DCI]

Pref. Location: Kolkata, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: senior software developer, requirement gathering, application support, agile methodology, software

testing,asp.net,javascript,jquery,ASP.Net MVC,SSRS,SQL Server

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

I have total 12+ Years of experience in software development.

Previously I have worked in Cognizant, Cognizant Softvision as a Senior Software Engineer. Currently I am not working. Technically proficient in MVC, ASP.Net, C#, MS SQL Server, Java Script, Jquery, Microsoft Azure. Involved in Design, Development, Administration, Maintenance and Support of projects

Team player with strong analytical, problem solving & organizational abilities.

Effective communicator with good interpersonal skills.

Work Experience

Cognizant Softvision as Senior Software Developer Nov 2018 to Till Date

Cognizant Softvision as Senior Software Developer Nov 2018 to Feb 2020

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Senior Developer Oct 2012 to May 2018

IntersoftKK Pvt Ltd as Senior Software Developer Jun 2011 to Aug 2012

Nexval Infotech as Senior Software Developer Sep 2010 to Jun 2011

Buildfusion Inc as Software Developer Aug 2008 to Sep 2010

Education

UG: B.Sc (Not Specified) from Calcutta University in 1998

PG: MCA (ER and DCI) from Electronic Research and Development Corporation of India in 2006

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

PGDCA (DOEACC A-LEVEL)

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
ASP.Net (2.0, 3.0, 3.5, 4.0), C#, WPF			
WF, WCF, VB 6.0, HTML, Java Script.			
ASP.Net (2.0, 3.0, 3.5, 4.0), WCF			
JQuery, JavaScript, SQL Server			
HTML, CSS, MVC Architecture, MVVM Archit			
SSIS, SSRS, MS CRM 4.0, Work Flow,			
html5, CSS3,			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Microsoft Azure, AWS			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Windows 7, Windows NT, Windows XP, 2000			
SQL Server 2000, 2005, 2008,2015			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
VSS,SVN,TFS,GIT			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Crystal Report, RDLC Report and SSRS			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Bengali	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Have H1 Visa

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time